No showgirl is safe on the streets of... Fear City.
Fear City is a drama, crime, mystery film directed by Abel Ferrara.
Strippers in Manhattan are being stalked and murdered by a psycho.
A hard-nosed police detective and a conflicted ex-boxer-turned-private-eye, hired by
the strip club owners, set out to find him before he strikes again.
Matt Rossi, played by Tom Berenger.
Al Wheeler, played by Billy Dee Williams.
Nicky Parzeno, played by Jack Scalia.
Loretta, played by Melanie Griffith.
Carmine, played by Rossano Brazzi.
Leila, played by Rae Dawn Chong.
Fear City is a 1984 American neo-noir erotic thriller film directed by Abel
Ferrara, and written by his longtime collaborator Nicholas St.
It stars Tom Berenger, Billy Dee Williams, Jack Scalia, and Melanie Griffith in the leading roles,
with supporting parts played by Rossano Brazzi, Rae Dawn Chong, Joe Santos, Michael V.
Gazzo and Jan Murray.
The film follows a former boxer turned mob-connected nightclub promoter (Berenger) and a fiercely driven police
Detective (Williams), investigating a brutal serial killer targeting strippers in Manhattan.
The title alludes to the Fear City pamphlets
distributed by the New York Police Department.
Fear City was Ferrara's first to be produced by a
major studio, 20th Century Fox.
However, it was distributed by independent company Aquarius Releasing.
It received mixed reviews.
The film explores themes of new york city,
nightclub, exploitation, vice, stripper.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.